Seymour S. Cohen Papers 1938-1990 Mss.Ms.Coll.48
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1940-1990; 11.5 linear feet
  - Veterans Administration Hospital, 1964 (Box 23)
  - Vincent, Walter S., 1951-1952 (Box 23)
  - Virology, 1957-1985 (Box 23)
    Balint, Robert F.; Luria, Salvador E.
  - Volk, Wesley A., 1954 (Box 23)
  - Volkin, Elliott, 1959-1966 (Box 23)
  - von der Haar, Friedrich, 1981 (Box 23)
  - Waddell, William R., 1970-1989 (Box 23)
  - Wagreich, Harry, 1973 (Box 23)
  - Wainwright, Stanley D., 1951-1954 (Box 23)
  - Wald, George, 1967-1969 (Box 23)
  - War Manpower Commission, 1944 (Box 23)
  - Warner, R.C., 1957 (Box 23)
  - Warren, Leonard, 1969-1984, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Warren, R.A.J., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Washington-Baltimore Enzyme Club, 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Washington University, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Wasternack, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Watson, James D., 1962 (Box 23)
  - Weber, George, 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Weber, Morton M., 1973 (Box 23)
  - Webster, D.A., 1970 (Box 23)
  - Wechter, William J., 1985 (Box 23)
  - Weed, Lawrence L., 1951-1954 (Box 23)
  - Weigle, Jean, 1956, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Weinbaum, George, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Weiner, Norman, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Weinhouse, Sidney, 1971, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Weinstein, David, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Weintraub, Harold, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Weisblat, David Irwin, 1987, 1990 (Box 23)
  - Weiser, C.J., 1979 (Box 23)
  - Weiss, Malcolm E., 1978 (Box 23)
  - Weiss, Samuel B., 1967-1970 (Box 23)
  - Weissbach, Herbert, 1975 (Box 23)
  - The Weizmann Institute of Science, 1982-1983 (Box 23)
  - Welch, Arnold D., 1956-1962 (Box 23)
  - Westengaard, Mogens (Box 23)
    -See Ser.I, Maalfe, Ole
  - Westphal, O., n.d. (Box 23)
  - Whitehead, R.G., 1970 (Box 23)
  - Whitley, Richard J., 1975 (Box 23)
  - Wigler, Paul W., 1971 (Box 23)
  - Wilhite, John, 1979 (Box 23)
  - Wilkins, M.H.F., 1958 (Box 23)
  - Williams, Charles H., Jr., 1970 (Box 23)
  - Williams, David L., 1978 (Box 23)
  - Williams, Harrison A., Jr., 1967 (Box 23)
  - Williams-Ashman, H. Guy, 1970-1981 (Box 23)
  - Wilson, D. Wright, 1954-1955 (Box 23)
  - Wilson, Irnie, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Winkler, Herbert, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Wimmer, Eckard, 1978, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Winters, Robert, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Wisseman, Charles L., Jr., 1976 (Box 23)
  - Witkin, Evelyn M., 1981 (Box 23)
  - Witkop, B., 1983 (Box 23)
  - Wollman, Elie, 1968-1974, n.d. (Box 23)
    Borek, Ernest
    -See also Ser.I, Borek, Ernest
  - Wood, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Wood, W.A., 1953 (Box 23)
  - Woodruff, H. Boyd, 1961, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Woolley, D.W., 1953 (Box 23)
  - Worcel, A., 1977 (Box 23)
  - World Health Organization, 1965-1983 (Box 23)
  - Worthington Biochemical Corporation, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Wu, Cheng-Wen, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Wu, Felicia Ying-Hsiueh, 1982-1983 (Box 23)
  - Wyatt, Gerard R., 1951-1974 (Box 23)
    -See also Ser.I, Merck, Sharpe and Dohme
    -See also Ser.I, Weed, Lawrence L.
  - Xu, Tungsen, [198-] (Box 23)
    -See also Ser.VI, Cohen, Seymour S. and Tungsen Xu
  - Yale University, 1979, 1984-1985 (Box 23)
  - Yamanaka, Kei, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Yamanoha, Banri, 1982-1985 (Box 23)
  - Yang, C.N., 1978 (Box 23)
  - Yoshuoka, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Zamecnik, Paul C., 1968, 1973, 1983-1984 (Box 23)
    Stephenson, Sis
  - Zappia, Vincenzo, 1980 (Box 23)
  - Zelle, Max R., 1972 (Box 23)
  - Zemlicka, Jirí, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Zgaga, Vera, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Ziff, Morris, 1981 (Box 23)
  - Zilliken, Fritz, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Zittle, Charles A., 1947 (Box 23)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1944-; 2 boxes; .75 linear feet
  Clippings, announcements and programs for lectures, some syllabi for courses, grant applications to the National Institutes of Health, meeting minutes for the American Cancer Society, research reports to the Commonwealth Fund, and a small amount of information about Scientists and Engineers for Johnson. Also in this series are Cohen's bibliography and some biographical material on Cohen, including descriptions of his research projects.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 24)
    -See Oversized
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1971-1978, n.d. (Box 24)
  - American Cancer Society, Inc. (Box 24)
    - Folder #1, 1957-1972 (Box 24)
    - Folder #2, 1973-Jun. 1975 (Box 24)
    - Folder #3, Oct. 1975-1985, n.d. (Box 24)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1962 (Box 24)
  - American Physiological Society, 1977, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics (Box 24)
  - Bacteriological Reviews, 1969 (Box 24)
  - Bibliography, 1986 (Box 24)
  - Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1967-1982 (Box 24)
  - Biographical Material, 1960-1964, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Borden Award, [1967] (Box 24)
    -See also Ser.I, Association of American Medical Colleges
  - "A Cellular System for the Study of Autumn"--Announcement for lecture, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, 1947-1972, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Clippings, 1950-1985, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Columbia University, 1967 (Box 24)
  - The Commonwealth Fund, 1948-1964, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Courses, 1953-1969 (Box 24)
  - Denver, 1975 (Box 24)
  - The Dreyfus Research Laboratories, 1965 (Box 24)
  - European Molecular Biology Organization, 1973 (Box 24)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, 1981 (Box 24)
  - The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1972, 1979 (Box 24)
  - The Heritage of Copernicus, 1972 (Box 24)
  - Howard University, 1965 (Box 24)
  - Indonesia--Human rights, 1978 (Box 24)
  - International Congress for Virology, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Journal of Medicinal Chemistry, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Kiskadden Lecture--Program, 1975 (Box 24)
  - Moscow--Human rights, 1985 (Box 24)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1971-1986 (Box 24)
  - National Cancer Plan, 1971 (Box 25)
  - The National Institute for Medical Research, 1964 (Box 25)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1969-1984 (Box 25)
  - Nucleic Acids Research, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Papanicolaou Cancer Research Institute, 1982, n.d. (Box 25)
  - The Passano Award, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Polyamines and Structure and Synthesis of Nucleic Acids--Announcement (Box 25)
  - The Rockefeller University, 1966 (Box 25)
  - Saint Jude Children's Research Hospital, 1972-1973 (Box 25)
  - Scientists and Engineers for Johnson, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Serbian Academy of Sciences and Arts, 1972 (Box 25)
  - Sigma Xi, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Société de Chimie Biologique, 1964 (Box 25)
  - The Society of American Bacteriologists, 1951 (Box 25)
  - The Society of General Physiologists, 1967-1971, n.d. (Box 25)
  - South Africa--Human rights, 1985 (Box 25)
  - State University of New York at Stony Brook, 1974-1984 (Box 25)
  - Symposium on Microbiology and Medical Research (Box 25)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - United States. Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1945, n.d. (Box 25)
  - United States. War Manpower Commission, 1944 (Box 25)
  - Université Catholique de Louvain, 1972 (Box 25)
  - Université de Bordeaux--Announcement for lecture (Box 25)
  - L'Université Libre de Bruxelles, 1967 (Box 25)
    -See also Oversized
  - University of Bologna--Announcement for lecture (Box 25)
  - University of Colorado, 1971-1975, n.d. (Box 25)
  - University of Kuopio, 1982 (Box 25)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1962-1971, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Vietnam, 1968 (Box 25)
  - Virus-Induced Enzymes--Reviews, 1968-1969 (Box 25)
  - The Weizmann Institute of Science, 1983 (Box 25)
- Series III. Works by Cohen, 1941-; 2 boxes; 0.5 linear feet
  Abstracts, typescripts, and some lectures. Some of the works were done with students (e.g., Hazel Barner Leung) and colleagues (e.g., Thomas F. Anderson). In these cases, cross-references have been made in Series IV. Included among the works is a lecture on Erwin Chargaff's work that Cohen gave when Chargaff was presented with the Carl Neuberg Medal in 1958. Also in this series is a manuscript of comments that Cohen wrote about his published papers while looking over the laboratory notebooks that are now contained in Series IV and V.
  - "The Binding of Polyamines and Ethidium to tRNA"--with Celia E. Freda, [197-] (Box 26)
    -See also Ser.V, "tRNA Studies. Binding of Spermidine, Ethidium..."
  - "A Biochemical Study of the Mutual Reactivation of Ultraviolet-Inactivated Bacteriophages in Their Host Bacteria"--Abstract with Rachel Arbogast, 28 Dec. 1949 (Box 26)
  - "Cancer Chemotherapy: A Study in Cellular Karate, Judo and Acupuncture"--Lecture at St. Jude Children's Research Hospital's 10th Anniversary, 17 Nov. 1972 (Box 26)
  - "Chemical Studies in Host-Virus Relationships. I. Effect of Bacteriophage Adsorption on Multiplication of Host, E. Coli B."--Abstract with Thomas F. Anderson, 1946 (Box 26)
  - "Chemical Studies in Host-Virus Relationships. II. Chemical Simulation of the Interference Phenomenon by 5-Methyl Tryptophane"--Abstract with Thomas F. Anderson, 1946 (Box 26)
  - "Chemical Studies on r+ and r Strains of Bacterial Viruses. I. Glucose Contents of Preparations of These Viruses and Their Isolated DNAs", [1956] (Box 26)
  - "Comments by S.S. Cohen on the Published Papers", Jul.-Dec. 1986 (Box 26)
  - "The Comparative Biochemistry of Virus Multiplication"--Abstract, n.d. (Box 27)
  - "D-Arabinosyl Nucleosides and the Sponge, Cryptotethya Crypta"--with Hazel Barner Leung, [196-] (Box 27)
  - "Debt to Foreign Research", 5 Nov. 1965 (Box 27)
  - Enzyme, Antigen, and Virus: A Study of Macromolecular Pattern in Action by Sir F. Macfarlane Burnet--Review, [1957] (Box 27)
  - "Enzymes Specified by DNA Phages", [1971] (Box 27)
  - "Erwin Chargaff: Scientist", 19 Mar. 1958 (Box 27)
  - "Evolutionary Biochemistry and the Evolution of Biochemistry", [1963] (Box 27)
  - "A Hemostatic and Its Application", 1944 (Box 27)
  - "Hope for All--In a Hospital", n.d. (Box 27)
  - "The Localization of Spermidine Synthase in Healthy and Virus-Infected Chinese Cabbage Protoplasts"--Abstract with Ram K. Sindhu, 1984 (Box 27)
  - "Metabolic Requirements for the Lethality of Bleomycin in E. Coli"--Abstract with Josephine I, n.d. (Box 27)
  - "Molecular Bases of the Parasitism of Some Bacterial Viruses", 27 Dec. (Box 27)
  - "The Molecular Biology of Viruses"--Introductory Remarks at Symposium at University of Alberta, Jun. 1966 (Box 27)
  - "The Nutritional Requirements of Virus Multiplication and the Chemotherapy of Viral Infections"--with Catherine B. Fowler (Box 27)
  - "On a Chemical Degradation of Desoxyribose Nucleic Acid" (Box 27)
    -See Ser.V, "Attempted Hydrolosis of NA by Dizomethane; Methylation of Nucleotides"
  - "On the Introduction of Radioactive Tracers into Virology", [1965] (Box 27)
  - "Polyamines and Macromolecular Polymer Synthesis During the Growth of Anacystis Nidulans"--with Seethala Ramakrishna, [197-] (Box 27)
  - "Properties of Ultracentrifugally Isolated Viruses Causing Tobacco Necrosis"--with Wendell M. Stanley, [ca. 1941] (Box 27)
    -See also Ser.V, "Isolation and Characterization of Tobacco Necrosis Viruses"
    -See also Ser.VI, "Properties of Ultracentrifugally..."
  - "Propylamine Transferases in the Healthy and Turnip Yellow Mosaic Virus-Infected Chinese Cabbage Leaves"--Abstract with Ram K. Sindhu (Box 27)
  - "Regulation of Biosynthesis"--Lecture, 1963 (Box 27)
  - "The Research Frontier: Where Is Science Taking Us?", 1957 (Box 27)
  - "S-Adenosyl-L-Methionine as a Pivotal Precursor for Polyamine and Ethylene Biosynthesis in Chinese Cabbage Protoplasts"--with Michael L. Greenberg, 1984 (Box 27)
  - "Some Data on the Incorporation of Exogenous Nutrients and on the Biosynthesis of Nucleic Acids and Proteins by E. Coli Strain TAU and on the Properties of "Synchronized" Cells"--with Janet Lichtenstein Stern, [196-] (Box 27)
  - "Some Studies on Bacteriophage Multiplication"--with Catherine B. Fowler, [195-] (Box 27)
  - Marjorie Stephenson and André Boivin--Tribute, [1950] (Box 27)
  - "Studies on Commercial Typhus Vaccines. V. The Nature of the Soluble Antigen of the Commercial Typhus Vaccine as Determined by a Quantitative Study of the Serological Cross Reactions of Rickettsial Fractions"--with Jean R. Clawson and Leslie A. Chambers, [194-] (Box 27)
  - "Synthesis in Virus-Infected Bacteria", [1950] (Box 27)
  - "Taking Care of Each Other", 25 Feb. 1971 (Box 27)
  - "Virus-Induced Enzymes and the Chemotherapy of Infectious Disease"--Lecture, [1978] (Box 27)
- Series IV. Works by Others, 1940-1983; 15 boxes; 7 linear feet
  Laboratory notebooks, laboratory notes, and some manuscripts. Most of the works were done by students and laboratory assistants in the 1960s. In the case of experiments that were carried out by more than one person, each person has been cross-referenced. The laboratory notebooks contain graphs, charts, photographs, and some test tubes (see Deborah Marcu, "Protoplasts"). There are many experiments by Judy Heyward, Lillie Lapi, Hazel Barner Leung, Janet Lichtenstein Stern, and Ellen Streibel. Subjects include polyamines, TYMV, bleomycin, ara-A, and adenine. Photographs have been left in this series, and extensive conservation work needs to be done (see Conservation Note).
  - "tRNA Studies"--Notes, 1971-1972; 2 Folders; Altendorf, C. (Box 28)
  - -See Ser.III, "Chemical Studies in Host-Virus Relationships...", Anderson, Thomas Foxen, 1911-1991 (Box 28)
  - "Progress in the Synthesis of a Substrate for Arginine-Specific Proteases", 21 Sep. 1981; Andrade, Patricia (Box 28)
  - -See Ser.III, "A Biochemical Study of the Mutual Reactivation...", Arbogast, Rachel (Box 28)
  - "Gene-Enzyme Relationship in Micro-Organisms", 1963; Bonner, David M. (Box 28)
  - -See Ser.IV, Clawson, Jean R. and Leslie A. Chambers. "Studies on Commercial Typhus Vaccines...", Chambers, Leslie A. (Box 28)
  - "Polyamines of TYMV; Serology; Adsorption of Polyamines and Removal; Density Gradients"--Notes, 1978-1979; 2 Folders; Champey, Elaine and Judy Heyward (Box 28)
  - "Virus Isolation; Polyamine Content; Adsorbed Polyamine and Removal"--Notes, 1978-1979; Champey, Elaine (Box 29)
  - -See also Ser.V, "Early Studies--Before Protoplasts", Champey, Elaine (Box 29)
  - "Polyamines in Red Algae", Apr. 1978; Cheng, Chung-Tai J. (Box 29)
  - "Studies on Commercial Typhus Vaccines. VI. Immunological Activity of Rickettsial Fractions and of the Soluble Antigen Preparations", [194-]; Clawson, Jean R. and Leslie A. Chambers (Box 29)
  - "A Study of the Arabinose Pathway in Mycobacteria and Cornebacteria: An Approach to Chemotherapy of Mycobacterial Diseases", [1983]; Cocito, Carlos G. (Box 29)
  - "Four Decades of Franco-American Collaboration in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology", [198-]; Cohen, Georges N. (Box 29)
  - "A Note on the Determination of Phosphate in the Presence of Interfering Substances", Delory, George Edward (Box 29)
  - "Bacterial Experiments"--Notes, 1965-1966; Doering, Alice (Box 29)
  - "Fractionation Studies", n.d.; Flaks, Joel G. (Box 29)
  - -See also Ser.IV, Leung, Hazel Barner and Joel G. Flaks. "Attempt to Infect Bacterial...", Flaks, Joel G. (Box 29)
  - "Nutritional Requirements of T2r+"--Notes, 1946-1947; 2 Folders; Fowler, Catherine B. (Box 29)
  - -See also Ser.III, "The Nutritional Requirements...", Fowler, Catherine B. (Box 29)
  - -See Ser.V, "Manometry of Cho Metabolism", Green, Maurice (Box 29)
  - "Studies on the Polyamines in TYMV", n.d.; Greenberg, Michael L. (Box 29)
  - -See also Ser.III, "S-Adenosyl-L-Methionine...", Greenberg, Michael L. (Box 29)
  - -See Ser.IV, Heyward, Judy and Linda Guarino. "Plant Log, Virus Preparation...", Guarino, Linda (Box 29)
  - "Biosynthesis of Cytosine Arabinoside 51 Phosphate", [196-]; Hamilton, R.D. (Box 29)
  - "Methods for Plants, TYMV Isolation, Serology, RNA, Polyamines of TYMV, Isolations of Chloroplasts"--Notes, 1976-1978; 2 Folders; Heyward, Judy (Box 29)
  - "Plant Log, Virus Preparation, Virus Properties; Search for SAM Decarboxylase in Anacystis"--Notes, 1976-1977; 3 Folders; Heyward, Judy and Linda Guarino (Box 30)
    -See also Ser.IV, Champey, Elaine and Judy Heyward. "Polyamines of TYMV..."
    -See also Ser.V, "Early Studies--Before Protoplasts"
    -See also Ser.V, Protoplasts
  - "Uptake of Putrescine in Seedlings; Isolation of Intact Chloroplasts; Metabolism by Intact Chloroplasts", 1979; Heyward, Judy (Box 30)
  - "Effects of Spermidine, Antibiotics on Polyauxotrophic E. Coli (AA-, U-); Studies with TAU1B; TAURC STR vs. TAURC REL + Methionine"--Notes, 1967; Hoffner, Nancy (Box 30)
  - "Attempted Activation of 21-Phosphate in Adenine-Containing Nucleotides by Irradiation"--Notes, 1967; Jansen, Miekie (Box 30)
  - "Strain TAUAd-ara Effects; Lethality of 2131 Dideoxyadenosine..."--Notes, 1965-1966; 2 Folders; Jansen, Miekie (Box 31)
  - "Binding of Ethidium Bromide by tRNA With or Without Polyamine as Studied by Spectrophotometric Measurement and Equilibrium Dialysis", 1976; I, Josephine (Box 31)
  - "Lethality of Bleomycin to E. Coli; Degradation of DNA by BLEO A5; Ethidium on E. Coli", 1975; I, Josephine (Box 31)
    -See also Ser.III, "Metabolic Requirements for the Lethality..."
  - "Production and Purification of R17, Extraction of RNA from R17 and Infectivity of R17 and R17 RNA on Bacteria and Blue Green Algae", [197-]; I, Josephine (Box 31)
  - "tRNA, Other Binding of Ethidium"--Notes, 1974; I, Josephine (Box 31)
  - -See also Ser.III, "Metabolic Requirements...", I, Josephine (Box 31)
  - "Fractionation of Cryptotethya Crypta", [195-]; Josten, J.J. (Box 31)
    -See also Ser.V, "Cryptotethya, ara A & B96..."
  - "A Conversion of Prolineless Mutants to Autotrophs by Means of Homologous Nucleic Acids", [1956]; Kanazir, Dusan and S. Subotic (Box 31)
  - "Tests of sp, spd, pu, Hirudenine, Arcaine on L Cells in Horse Sera"--Notes, 1966; Keller, Joan (Box 31)
  - "Toxic Compounds on L Cells"--Notes, 1966; Keller, Joan (Box 31)
    - Folders #1-2 (Box 31)
    - Folders #3-4 (Box 32)
  - -See Ser.V, "Manometry of Cho Metabolism", Lanning, M. (Box 32)
  - "Bacterial Growth; Inhibition by Fluorouracil Derivatives; Effects of DMSD; Effects of 3H-ara AMP"--Notes, 1969-1970; Lapi, Lillie (Box 32)
  - "Bleomycin I"--Notes, 1975; 2 Folders; Lapi, Lillie (Box 32)
  - "Bleomycin II"--Notes, 1975-1976; 2 Folders; Lapi, Lillie (Box 32)
  - "Chemical Methods for Plants; Isolations of Plant RNA; RNA-Polyamines; Valine Acceptance"--Notes, 1974-1975; 2 Folders; Lapi, Lillie (Box 33)
  - "Properties of Chinese Cabbage Leaves..."--Notes, 1973-1974; 2 Folders; Lapi, Lillie (Box 33)
  - "Toxicity of ara A1 Deoxyadenosine, and Adenosine to L Cells..."--Notes, 1975-1976; 2 Folders; Lapi, Lillie (Box 33)
  - -See also Ser.V, "Chemical Methods. ara A Nucleosides and Nucleotides; Animal Cell Culture; Bacterial Culture; Turnip Yellow Mosaic Virus; Chloroplasts" -See also Ser.V, "Effects of Ethidium on TAUst, TAUxel; Bacterial Growth, Some Methods" -See also Ser.V, "Incorporation of Labeled araA and araAMP into L Cells" -See also Ser.V, "L Cell Reserves; Lethality of Nucleosides and Nucleotides; DMSO Effects; Cloning" -See also Ser.V, "Ornithine Decarboxylase in E. Coli" -See also Ser.V, "Preparation of araAMP, + 3H + 32P; Isolation of araA Nucleotides..." -See also Ser.V, "Syntheses, Labeled Nucleotides. araA (r) araAMP (r) araATP", Lapi, Lillie (Box 33)
  - "15T-: Pyrimidine Requirements, Phage Sensitivity, Adsorption, Phage Production", 1952-1953; 2 Folders; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 34)
  - "Adenine Mutants, Including TAUAd...", 1963-1965; 2 Folders; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 34)
  - "Attempt to Infect Bacterial Protoplasts with DNA"--Notes, 1957-1958; Leung, Hazel Barner and Joel G. Flaks (Box 34)
  - "Attempted Isolation of Mutants Deficient in Deoxycytidine Deaminase and/or Nucleoside Phosphorylase", 1961-1962; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 34)
  - "Auxotrophic Mutants: Pyrimidineless; 15T-Amino Acid-Less; Methods"--Notes, 1955-1957; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 34)
  - "Effect of T2 Infection on Enzyme Content", [195-]; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 34)
  - "Effects of Inhibitors"--Notes, 1953-1957; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 34)
    - Folder #1 (Box 34)
    - Folder #2 (Box 35)
  - "Fluorouracil and Thymineless Death; Activity of F-Pyrimidine Nucleosides...", 1957-1960; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 35)
  - "HMase, TSase in T- + Infection..."--Notes, 1958-1959; 2 Folders; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 35)
  - "Nucleic Acid and Acid-Soluble Components of Cryptotethya Crypta and M. Tuberculosis; Metabolic Activities and Variability of Sponge Cells", 1961-1963; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 35)
  - "On 15T- Adaptation to Xylose"--Notes, 1953-1956; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 35)
  - "Phage Stocks, New Cultures, Thymineless Effects, CDR Deaminase, Pyrimidine Nucleoside Phosphorylase, Green Hydrogenation"--Notes, 1953-1957; 2 Folders; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 35)
  - "Radiated Phage and Early (H Mase) & Late (Lysozyme) Enzymes, TAUAd, Miscellaneous"--Notes, 1964; 2 Folders; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 36)
  - "Relations of RNA and DNA Synthesis to Inducibility Use of 15T-U-"--Notes, 1958-1959; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 36)
  - "Ribonucleotide Reductase; Studies on dCMP Deaminase..."--Notes, 1960-1964; 2 Folders; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 36)
  - "Search for Infectious DNA in Infected DNA; Use of Resistant Strains Protoplasts"--Notes, 1959; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 36)
  - "Tests of Dihydro- and CH2OH- Derivatives on Mutants; Effects of DNAse on Thymus r+ & r DNA; Electrophoresis of Digests; Fuculose Phosphate"--Notes, 1955-1956; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 37)
  - "Thymineless Bacteria: Sulfanilamide as a Bactericide..."--Notes, 1952-1956; Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 37)
    -See also Ser.III, "D-Arabinosyl Nucleosides..."
    -See also Ser.IV, Stern, Janet Lichtenstein and Hazel Barner Leung. "Conversion of Phage-Induced RNA..."
    -See also Ser.V, "Manometry of Cho Metabolism"
  - -See also Ser.III, "D-Arabinosyl Nucleosides..." -See also Ser.IV, Stern, Janet Lichtenstein and Hazel Barner Leung. "Conversion of Phage-Induced RNA..." -See also Ser.V, "Manometry of Cho Metabolism", Leung, Hazel Barner (Box 37)
  - "Preparation of 51 Nucleotides", [195-]; Loeb, Marilyn Rosenthal, 1930- (Box 37)
  - "The Effect of Arabinosyl-ADP and d-ADP on Polynucleotide Phosphorylase from E. Coli", [1965]; Lucas-Lenard, Jean (Box 37)
  - -See Ser.V, "Attempt to Sensitize TAUAd to araAMP" -See Ser.V, "Incorporation of Labeled araA and araAMP into L Cells" -See Ser.V, "L Cell Reserves; Lethality of Nucleosides and Nucleotides; DMSO Effects; Cloning", Manduka, M.J. (Box 37)
  - -See Ser.IV, Schwarz, Ruth. "Activity of ara A on TAUAd...", Marble, Mary (Box 37)
  - "Protoplasts (r) Chloroplasts"--Notes, 1980-1981; Marcu, Deborah (Box 37)
    - Folder #1 (Box 37)
    - Folders #2-3 (Box 38)
  - "Sephadex Separations of RNA..."--Notes, 1979; 2 Folders; Marcu, Deborah (Box 38)
  - -See also Ser.V, Protoplasts, Marcu, Deborah (Box 38)
  - "Tests of Dansyl Method; Polyamines in Nucleates", Morgan, Sophia (Box 38)
    -See Ser.V, same title
  - -See Ser.V, "Incorporation of Labeled araA and araAMP into L Cells", Ortiz, P. (Box 38)
  - "Enzyme Induction in E. Coli BU-", Dec. 1958; Pizer, Lewis I. (Box 38)
  - "Investigation of Phage-Induced Dihydrofolate Reductase", 29 Aug. 1968; Plunkett, William K., Jr. (Box 38)
  - "Lethality of araA, araAMP to TAUAd; Effects of Methylioadenosine and Analogues on TAUAd", Plunkett, William K., Jr. (Box 38)
  - "Separation of tRNA-Spermidine Complex; Thiouridine in E. Coli tRNA"--Notes, 1971; Pochon, François (Box 38)
  - "tRNA Studies. Binding of Spermidine Ethidium...", Prairie, Celia Esther Freda (Box 38)
  - -See Ser.V, "Manometry of Cho Metabolism", Raff, R. (Box 38)
  - "Polyamines and: Levorphanol, Thymineless, Viability, Antibiotics, Anaerobiosis, and Methionineless"--Notes, 1966; Raina, Aarne (Box 38)
  - -See Ser.III, "Polyamines and Macromolecular...", Ramakrishna, Seethala (Box 38)
  - "TAU Killed by Streptomycin in T & U Contains Active Ribosomes"--Notes, 1966; Rinker, Bob (Box 38)